## Hello

# I'm Kirsten Vandepas

CLIFTON PARK, NY 12065 (518) 275-5692 KIRSTENMATAN@GMAIL.COM

Portfolio: https://kvandepas.myportfolio.com/

I'm a New York based Digital Designer who is unafraid of complicated requirements, whether building from the ground up or adhering to branding guidelines. I bring years of experience from a multitude of media to craft elegant user interfaces with an emphasis on the end-user experience.

# **Experience**

JUNE 2022 - PRESENT

#### **Creatacor**, **Clifton Park NY** - 2D Graphic Production Designer

- Communicator and inter-departmental collaborator
- Ensure brand standards and have an excellent understanding of color, graphic processes, image quality, and production methods
- Ability to adhere to project deadlines while maintaining a high level of detail, accuracy, and quality
- Work at a fast, energetic pace and be able to multi-task while managing a variety of projects
- Work in Photoshop, InDesign, and Illustrator Work with Roland printers in VersaWorks
- Presentation and communication skills
- Update Social Media
- Meet with manager/supervisor and project managers to come up with thoughtful and sound troubleshooting ideas when problems arise
- Time management skills
- Working closely with both internal and external production teams to bring concepts to reality
- Effectively communicate all project-related progress, issues or concerns to the Design Manager and other Project Management teams in a timely and professional manner
- Update and maintain quality materials for the production of graphics
- Responsible for the cleaning and maintenance of all Graphic Production equipment
- Purchasing of all materials, but not limited to, required by the production room
- Executing Purchasing Orders, managing vendor relationships and estimating for Graphic RFE projects

APRIL 2019 - JUNE 2022

## Adirondack Sign Company, Saratoga Springs NY - Designer

- Create design layouts for signage (building, dimensional, carved, vehicle wraps, digital vinyl).
- Vectorize and recreate company logos.
- Edit clients' artwork to become print ready.

- Set up files for print, flatbed, and router.
- Work directly with clients via phone or email on project design.
- Work with supervisor to submit design proposals to different towns for permit/DRC approval.
- Assisting with production using Roland printers to print media onto vinyl and contour cut colored vinyl.
- Create estimates & invoices; take payments & deposits.
- Customer service greeting, answering phones and taking payments.

#### FFBRUARY 2016 - OCTOBER 2018

### **Level Up Studios, Albany NY** - Client Manager / Product Designer

- Advise clients on attainable goals and develop project plans.
- Manage full project life cycle for clients and ensure top quality deliverables.
- Work with artists to create merchandise for their products.
- Work with different print shops and bulk companies directly to make sure art is correctly formatted for ordering products.
- Travel to conventions to bring in new clients and sell current clients merchandise.

#### NOVEMBER 2015 - FEBRUARY 2016

#### **Gracenote**, Queensbury NY - Digital Image Editor

- Collect photos, logos and other digital assets from publicists and websites.
- Place collect logos with correct film/tv show.
- Create logos for shows/specials with no artwork.
- Work within a team to divide and conquer requests from the station.

#### JUNE 2013 - OCTOBER 2013

#### Dark Square FX, Brooklyn NY - Funior Compositor

- Integrate generated images into live action footage.
- Create 2D graphic elements.
- Edit material to match film noise and colors accordingly.
- Roto around objects to be taken out of scenes.

### Education

#### NOVEMBER 2021 - NOVEMBER 2022

#### **CareerFoundry** - Technical Degree in UI/UX Design

Learned from industry professionals about user interface and experience to create applications from researching, wireframing, and prototyping to final designs across different platforms (IOS, Android, Tablet, Web).

#### SEPTEMBER 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2012

### **The DAVE School** - *Technical Degree in Animation & Visual Effects*

Worked with industry professionals to learn animation, modeling, compositing and visual effects.

**SEPTEMBER 2008 - JUNE 2010** 

## F. Donald Myers Education Center - Technical Degree in Graphic Design

Learned the adobe suite to complete different lessons such as; web design, photography, logo design, print design.

# **Programs/Skills**

• Adobe Suite (Photoshop, Indesign, Illustrator, XD, etc.) • Microsoft Suite • Flexi Design • Roland Versaworks • Quickbooks • Production File Setup • Typography • Figma • Graphic Design • Layout Design • UI/UX Design • Prototyping • Brand Guidelines • Print Design • HTML/CSS/JavaScript • Responsive Web Design • Wireframing • Vector Illustration • Project Management •